恶魔城
第四季 第10集 全剧终
‎你该上床睡觉了
It's nearly your bedtime.
‎我还没说完
I'm not finished yet.
‎你可能还没说完 ‎不过葡萄酒供应肯定是完了
You might not be, but the wine supply is definitely over.
‎一切都完了 赫克托
Oh, it's all over, Hector.
‎真的没有完
It's really not.
‎只是世道变了 ‎仅此而已
Things just changed, that's all.
‎吸血鬼不喜欢改变
Vampires aren't big on change.
‎那你之前应该告诉卡米拉的
Someone should have told Carmilla that.
‎你还是误会她了
You still misunderstand her.
‎拜托
Oh, come on.
‎连你都被她变成的样子吓到了
Even you were horrified by what she turned into.
‎也许是因为她计划的庞大
The scale of it, maybe.
‎还有可能给我们的生活带来的混乱
And the chaos it would have introduced into our lives.
‎我还是要说 一切的根源
I still say that at the root of it all
‎都在于吸血鬼的属性
was the vampire's virtue.
‎我们希望一切都保持原样
We want everything to remain the same.
保持稳定
To remain stable.
‎吸血鬼的属性 该死
The vampire's virtue. Bloody hell.
‎一直以来都有这种哲学把戏
There's an act of philosophical acrobatics for the ages.
‎你想要变聪明时应该闭嘴
Oh, shush with your trying to be clever.
‎你们这些人花了60年时间 ‎横冲直撞
You people spend 60 years bumping into things
然后管这叫生活
and call it a life.
‎我们得从更长远来考虑
We have to take a longer view.
‎所以我们想要稳定
So we want stability.
‎你是说你们曾经很稳定
And you're saying you had that.
‎的确
We did.
‎作为四人组 ‎我和我的姐妹们有力量
As a quartet, my sisters and I had strength.
‎维持稳定环境的力量
The strength to enforce a stable environment.
‎力量可以用来发动战争 确实
Strength can fight a war, yes,
‎但也可以用来创建庇护所
but it can also build a shelter.
‎你听懂了吗
Are you following me?
‎只是过程中会出现一些状况
Just bumping into things along the way.
‎小团体比大团体更稳固 丽诺尔
Small shapes are stronger than big ones, Lenore.
‎卡米拉想要的不仅仅是遮蔽风雨的庇护所
Carmilla wanted more than a weatherproof shelter.
‎最终是这样
In the end.
不过一切 ‎都源自吸血鬼的属性 你明白吗
But it all came from that virtue, do you see?
‎力量和权力截然不同
Strength and power are different.
‎你要的是力量
You wanted strength.
‎卡米拉想要权力
Carmilla wanted power.
‎到头来 没错
In the end, yes.
是变成了这样
That's what it turned into.
‎结果也毁了我的生活
Which is what ruined my life.
‎权力
Power.
‎巨大的 国际的
Big, international,
非外交 部署权力
non-diplomatic, projected power
‎是另一回事
is something else.
‎它借给你更多威力
It lends you more might,
‎不过却不能当作力量
but it doesn't have the utilities of strength.
‎它会让你彻底失败
It lays eggs in you.
‎它会变成你必须喂养的寄生虫
It becomes a parasite you have to feed.
‎权力除了侵蚀 什么也不做
Power does nothing but eat.
‎就像吸血鬼
Like a vampire.
‎所以...
Therefore...
‎展现出真正的自我...
having been shown what I am...
‎发现自己一直生活在谎言中
having found that I have been living a lie...
‎结果我还是坐在笼子里 ‎就像被关起来的危险动物
here I sit in a cage, like a dangerous animal.
快乐的杂种 艾萨克国王
With King Isaac, the happy bastard,
‎一直密切监视着我的生活
keeping a very watchful eye on me.
‎我从未见他这么开心过
I've never known him so fucking cheerful.
‎这很匪夷所思
It's bizarre.
‎不过他不会伤害你
But he won't harm you.
‎是啊
No.
他只是想把我关在笼子里
He's just going to keep me in a cage.
‎我不会在笼子里坐以待毙的 赫克托
And I'm not going to sit in a cage, Hector.
‎即便是跟你一起
Not even with you.
‎我为你所经历的一切深感抱歉
I'm sorry for everything you went through.
‎我很抱歉不能在这里帮你完成...
And I'm sorry I can't be here to help you through...
‎接下来的任何事情
whatever comes next.
‎不过我拒绝像这样活着
But I refuse to exist like this.
‎我想看看你总是提到的太阳
And I want to see what's so special
‎到底有多么特别
about this sun you keep talking about.
‎丽诺尔 别这样
Lenore, don't.
‎赫克托 ‎没关系
Hector, it's fine.
‎这是我想做的事
It's what I want to do.
‎随你 丽诺尔
Be free, Lenore.
‎你打算怎么办
What will you do?
‎我想 我会写本书
I think I'm going to write a book.
‎未来的人们应该知道我们所犯的错误
The future should know the mistakes we made.
‎最近 我明白了 ‎比我活得更久的...
And recently, I've been caused to know the value...
‎那些事物的...
and the beauty...
价值和美好
of things that live longer than I do.
‎就只是这样吗
Is that all there is to it?
‎赫克托 你真是个傻瓜
Hector, you are a silly man.
‎你觉得我的计划怎么样
So, what do you think about my plan?
‎这是我的计划
It was my plan.
‎你只是觉得这是你的计划
You just think it was your plan.
‎就是我的计划
It was my plan.
‎我让你觉得这是你的计划
I let you think it was your plan.
‎我把我的计划告诉了你
I told you my plan.
‎你只是觉得你告诉我了
You just think you did.
我很聪明
I'm very clever.
‎我把我的计划告诉了你 ‎让你觉得
I told you my plan in a way that would make you think
这是你自己的主意
it was your idea.
本来就是我自己的主意
It was my bloody idea.
‎承认吧 你被打败了
Admit it. You're outmatched.
‎我才不是那种人 ‎而且 这都是我的主意
I am no such thing, and also it was all my idea.
‎你就这么去想吧
You just go on thinking that.
‎所以 你答应了吗
So you agree, then?
‎答应什么
Agree to what?
‎我的计划
My plan.
我们打算留下来
We're going to stay.
-‎这下糟了  -‎我是个天才
- Oh, my God. - I'm a genius.
屈服吧
Just surrender.
‎暂且不说
Ignoring for a moment
‎你比我之前预计的要疯狂得多
that you are considerably more insane than I have previously estimated.
‎你确定这是个好主意吗
Are you sure it's a good idea?
我是说 ‎我不...
I mean, I'm not...
习惯与人交往
used to people.
‎他们已经习惯你了
They're used to you.
‎所以 让他们习惯你吧
So just let them be used to you.
然后你就会习惯他们
And you'll get used to them.
‎我觉得 为了试着理解这个逻辑
I think I felt part of my brain die
我的一部分大脑快死了
just trying to follow that logic.
‎他们是人类 适应了就好了
It's human. Just roll with it.
‎我不是
I'm not.
‎不是人类
Human, I mean.
‎不完全是人类
Not completely.
‎别以为我没注意到
Don't think I haven't noticed you
‎你跟孤儿们玩在一起
playing with the orphaned kids.
‎别以为我不知道
And don't think I don't know
‎他们之中有人管你叫"爸爸"
some of them have been calling you "father."
‎我...
I...
‎我不想说些什么让他们失望
I didn't want to disappoint them by saying anything.
‎你很有人性
Very human of you.
‎阿鲁卡多 你真是个奇怪的人
You, Alucard, are a very odd person.
‎我觉得我可能会喜欢你
I think I might like you.
‎阿鲁卡多 她出现了
Alucard, she's up.
‎温和点
Be gentle.
‎她已经两周没跟任何人说过话了
She hasn't talked to anyone in two weeks now.
‎赛珐
Sypha.
‎你好
Hello.
‎你能腾匹马给我吗
Can you spare a horse?
‎也许吧 拿来干嘛
Possibly. What for?
‎我要去做特雷弗和我原本计划做的事
I am going to do what Trevor and I originally planned to do.
‎回到我的车队里
Rejoin my caravan.
‎你知道你在这里很受欢迎
You know you are very welcome here.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎不过我也非常肯定自己怀孕了
But I am also very definitely pregnant.
‎我应该跟我的族人在一起
And I should be with my people.
‎而且我的族人很擅长
And my people are well practiced
‎在需要时给女人应有的支持
in giving the support a woman needs when it's time.
‎要是我能得到一匹马就好了
If I could just get a horse.
‎恭喜你
Congratulations.
‎继续
Go on.
‎就像我们到达庄园时
Say it like the way you said it to Trevor
‎你对特雷弗说的那样
when we arrived at the Hold.
‎我不该恭喜吗
Should I not be congratulating?
"公洗"
Congratulations.
我还听过更糟糕的发音呢
Well, I've heard worse impressions.
没事
It's fine.
‎他爱我
He loved me.
‎我们有了孩子
We made a child.
‎这一切会带来崭新而美好的事物
Something new and wonderful will have come from all this.
‎我该走了
I should go.
‎你应该留下来
You should stay.
‎你的好意我心领了
That's very kind of you.
‎不过我应该跟更多人在一起
But I should be around more people.
‎我不能让你成为我唯一依赖的求助对象
I can't let you be the one person I rely on for help,
‎而且孩子应该有一个群体
and a child should have a community.
‎如果你留下来 ‎就会有的
It will. If you stay.
‎我不明白
I don't understand.
‎这些人不用回德内什蒂
These people aren't going back to Danesti.
‎我们要围绕着城堡和庄园
We're going to found a new village here,
建一个新的村子
around the castle and the Hold.
‎这个地方有资源
This place has resources
‎这是我在德内什蒂给不了我的人民的
I could never give my people in Danesti.
‎我们可以改变这里的一切
We could change everything here.
‎我们会有学校
We're going to have schools,
‎其中一个学校将是关于
one of which will be all about the libraries
‎城堡和庄园的图书馆
of the castle and the Hold.
‎我希望你能帮我教教
And I was hoping you could help me teach
‎这个才华横溢却相当没用的男人
this brilliant but actually fairly useless man
‎如何生活
how to live his life.
‎不要抱太大的希望
Don't set your hopes too high.
‎赛珐 ‎我们有真正的机会
Sypha, we have a real chance
‎让我们的孩子比我们
to make life better for our children
‎生活得更好
than it was for us.
‎这一次 还能更好
For once, it could be better.
对我们所有的孩子来说都是
For all our children.
‎她真会说
She's good.
‎我知道
I know.
‎你有大麻烦了
You're in real trouble.
‎你们打算把这个村子叫什么
What are you going to call the village?
‎新德内什蒂吗
New Danesti?
‎我想我们可以取名为贝尔蒙特
I thought we might call it Belmont.
‎这应该会让所有人都感到困惑
That should confuse everybody.
‎我想我会很乐意住在 ‎一个叫贝尔蒙特的地方
I think I'd like to live in a place called Belmont.
‎而且 ‎天啦
Also, my God,
这些人的组织能力太差
these people are bad at organization.
‎你们真的打算一整天都从河里‎来来回回
And are you really going to walk buckets back and forth
运送水桶吗
from the river all day?
‎我还以为你懂科学呢
I thought you were a man of science.
‎那边的小路也需要拓宽
The lane's going to need widening over there too.
‎那是谁的马
Whose horse is that?
‎什么马
What horse?
‎沿小路走着的那匹
Walking down the lane.
‎把你的马拴起来 阿鲁卡多
Tie your horses up, Alucard.
‎如果你要建个村子
If you're founding a village,
‎就需要把这些东西都整理好
you need to sort these things out.
‎我认识那匹马
I know that horse.
‎不过...
But...
‎马上有人
someone's on it.
你好啊 亲爱的
Hello, love.
怎么会
How?
怎么回事
What?
所有问题
All the questions.
‎你赶紧回答
You answer now.
‎我能想到的就是 ‎圣日耳曼
All I can think of is that Saint Germain
在死之前打开了无限回廊
opened the Infinite Corridor just before he died.
‎我把匕首插进了死神的身体
I got the dagger into Death.
‎他像太阳一样发起光来
He lit up like the sun.
‎不一会儿 我就到了回廊里面
A second later I was inside the corridor.
‎接下来当我意识到时 ‎已经脸朝下
Next thing I knew, I was lying on my face
躺在多瑙河北岸了
by the north bank of the Danube.
‎真是没想到啊
Well, I'll be damned.
‎我们这里需要帮助 马上
We need some help over here right now!
‎我会没事的
I'll be okay.
‎我只是需要睡上一年 换个新的躯体
I just need about a year's sleep and a new body.
‎那你呢
What about you?
‎一切都好吗
Is everything all right?
‎我很好
I'm fine.
‎那就好
Good.
‎你知道最让我害怕的是什么吗
You know what scared me the most?
‎什么
What?
‎你最终可能会给孩子起名叫特雷弗
That you might end up calling the kid Trefor after all.
‎你怎么知道的
How did you even know?
‎拜托 ‎是我啊
Please. This is me.
‎你觉得我是如何做到
How do you think I've managed
‎一直单身并且了无牵挂的
to stay single and carefree all these years?
‎谁能过来杀了这个男人吗
Can someone please come over here and kill this man?
现在杀我应该很容易
It won't be hard.
‎你真是个粗鲁的白痴 ‎特雷弗·贝尔蒙特
You are a rude idiot, Trevor Belmont.
‎我知道
I know.
‎可我爱你
And I love you.
‎这我也知道
I know.
‎我说了 这个男人需要帮助
I said this man needs help.
‎你好 贝尔蒙特
Hello, Belmont.
‎那把匕首是怎么回事
Now what was that trick with the dagger?
‎你好 阿鲁卡多
Hello, Alucard.
‎士兵们在塔哥维斯特的
Well, there were fighters in Targoviste
藏身之处
hiding in what turned out to be
‎原来是王家的宝藏库
the royal family's treasure vault,
‎他们只是把东西从那里拿出来
and they were just taking things out of there
并且当成护身符
as good-luck charms.
‎我开始注意到一些东西
I started noticing things.
‎最后收集到了‎一位疯狂的巫师铁匠
Ended up collecting the pieces of something
‎曾经制造过的物件碎片
a mad wizard blacksmith once made to enact
‎一件用来跟上帝订立单方面的谋杀自杀契约的物件
a very one-sided murder-suicide pact with God.
‎所以...
So...
‎所以 ‎你很清楚当你使用这东西时 ‎对你来说
So you knew the thing was probably lethal to you
可能是致命的
when you used it.
‎不过我也没有选择的余地
But didn't see much of a choice.
‎这些人在这里做什么
What are all these people doing here?
‎欢迎来到我的村子
Welcome to my village.
‎你现在有个村子了吗
You have a village now?
‎它叫什么名字
What's it called?
‎小特雷弗
Treffy.
‎谁能过来杀了我吗
Can someone please come over here and kill me?
‎你看起来怪开心的
You look weirdly happy.
‎我...
I...
‎我确实怪开心的
I weirdly am.
‎这真是一段奇特的旅程
It's been a strange ride.
‎我很高兴一切都结束了
I'm happy it's over.
‎有趣的是 我生平第一次
The funny thing is, for the first time in my life,
‎完全不知道接下来会发生什么
I have absolutely no idea what happens next.
‎我只是有一种一切都会值得的感觉
I just have this feeling that it's going to be worth it.
‎就是这样
That's exactly it.
‎我怪开心的
I'm weirdly happy.
‎你还好吗
Are you all right?
应该是吧
I think so?
‎我想我们终于赢了
I think we finally won.
丽莎·特佩斯和弗拉德·特佩斯
Lisa and Vlad Tepes.
‎那...
So.
‎你得习惯叫自己弗拉德
You need to get used to calling yourself Vlad.
‎我想是这样
I suppose so.
‎我不能把你介绍为
I can't be introducing you as
"德古拉·特佩斯 老实说 没关系
"Dracula Tepes, honestly no relation,
别凑近看他的牙"
don't look too closely at his teeth."
‎你想跟我说的就是这个吗
Is this what you really want to talk about?
‎我死了
I died.
‎你不在那里
And you weren't there.
‎我知道
I know.
‎然后你也死了
And you died.
‎是的
I did.
‎然后你来找我了
And you came to find me.
‎当然了
Of course I did.
你肯定会来找你
I could do nothing else.
‎我以为你还有别的选择
I assumed you had other options.
‎对着撒旦大喊大叫 直到他承认
Shouting at Satan until he admitted
‎他只是在给你暖椅子
he was just keeping the chair warm for you.
‎那一类的事
That sort of thing.
‎我死去的那一刻
The second after I died
‎可能是你死后我第一次清醒的时刻
might have been the first sane moment I had since you died.
‎你看起来确实非常平静
You do seem remarkably calm.
‎而你看起来好像有点生气
And you seem a little angry.
‎因为这些都没有任何意义
Because none of this makes any sense.
‎你对发生的事情有什么理论吗
Do you have a theory about what happened?
‎你怎么会认为我有理论
What makes you think I have a theory?
‎你是男人 男人总是有理论
You're a man. Men always have theories.
‎我只知道 我们昨天在田野中醒来
All I know is that we woke up in a field yesterday.
‎还偷了一些衣服 ‎我对此还是觉得过意不去
And had to steal some clothes. I still feel bad about that.
今天下午
You didn't feel bad
‎你偷那个工头钱包时 却没有觉得过意不去
about picking that headman's pocket this afternoon.
‎他就是头猪
Well, he was a pig.
‎不过我们应该为那些
But we should do something
被我们拿走了衣服的人做点什么 明天吧
for the people we took these clothes from tomorrow.
‎我们会的
And we will.
‎不过在那之后...
But after that?
‎我们不能回到城堡了
We can't return to the castle.
‎我们可怜的孩子 ‎应该给他的生活做个了结
Our poor boy deserves some closure in his life.
‎也许会在未来的某一天
Perhaps, one day in the future.
‎但还不是时候
But not yet.
‎不是
No.
‎我有个想法
I have a thought.
‎不是理论吗
Not a theory?
‎不是理论 只是想法
Not a theory. Just a thought.
‎我觉得我们应该去旅行
I think we should travel.
‎去哪里
Where to?
‎我在想英国
I was thinking about England.
‎东北海岸有个地方
There's a place on the northeast coast
那里应该很美
that is supposed to be beautiful.
‎他们说 那里几乎没有阳光
And they say the sun barely shines there.
‎是叫怀特比还是惠特比之类的
White-by, or Whitby, something like that.
‎我猜那里偏远又孤独
Remote and lonely, I presume?
‎一座修道院 有男有女
An abbey. Men and women.
‎据说还有大约20栋房子
And about 20 houses, I've read.
‎还有海景 和鱼
Sea views. Fish.
‎鱼吗 那我怎么能拒绝
Fish. How can I resist?
‎没有你 我是不会好起来的
I'm not going to get better without you.
‎没有你 我也绝对不会好起来的
And I was never going to be better without you.
‎我们有了第二次机会
We have a second chance.
‎还有一个崭新的未来
And a brand-new future.